stubhub.com 2009-03-19

# Tickets at StubHub! Where Fans Buy and Sell Tickets

Privacy Policy

_Please Note:  
As of 3/14/07 we have made changes to our Privacy Policy_

**Overview**

StubHub is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.StubHub.com. Because StubHub wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

Users with questions or concerns regarding their privacy or this statement should contact StubHub Customer Service at:

> StubHub, Inc.  
>  199 Fremont, 3rd Floor  
>  San Francisco, CA 94105  
>  Telephone: 1.866.StubHub  
>  Email: [customerservice@stubhub.com](mailto:customerservice@stubhub.com)

If they do not receive acknowledgment of their inquiry or their inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, they should then contact TRUSTe through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process ( _http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php_ )](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the website to resolve users concerns. 

**Information Collection**

_What We Collect_   
When you **browse** through our site we collect: 

  * Basic information about your computer, browser and connection to make sure that we can give you proper information and customer service and for security purposes.
  * Aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit to improve our site.

If you choose to **register** , so that you can buy or sell tickets, we will ask you for more information including:

  * Your name and address which, among other things, enables us to have your tickets picked up or delivered to you;
  * Your email address and telephone number so we can contact you;
  * Your date of birth which, among other things, ensures that all of our users are adults and provides us general demographic information;
  * A login and password to use to update your information at any time in the future.

If you choose to **buy** or **sell** tickets we will ask you for: 

  * Credit card information to complete your transaction (for buyers) or to verify your identity (for sellers). 
  * Shipping address so tickets can be shipped to the location of your choice.

_Changing and Updating Personal Information; Choosing Options:_  
Consumers can change all of their personal account information by going to the My Account page <https://www.stubhub.com/account> and clicking the "Edit Account Info" button. You can change your address, telephone number, email address, password, credit card information, as well as your privacy settings. Also on this page we will give you the option to choose if you would like to receive email or written service from StubHub. If you would like to receive these solicitations simply check the appropriate box. You can choose to stop participating at any time simply by changing your preferences on the website, replying to an email's Unsubscribe function, or contacting Customer Service. Please refer to the _Choice and opt-out_ section for more information.

_Supplementing Information:_  
We may obtain information from or about you in other ways. For example, we may verify user information with a service provider, or users may send us information during their contacts with Customer Support.  

_Co-Branded Partners:_  
Co-branded sites are sites that appear labeled with another company's logos or trademarks. As indicated herein, information collected on co-branded pages hosted by StubHub is collected by co-branded partners. The contact information and transaction data (excluding credit card numbers) provided by customers on our co-branded sites and registered or transacted through the partner's co-branded 'StubHub' are essentially shared by StubHub and the owner of that co-branded website. Your choices about being contacted are included with that information so that partner may respect your preferences. However, please understand StubHub does not control information actually owned by co-branded partners. Please refer to their respective privacy policies for information on how they will handle your information. All information provided by you will be used according to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**Profile**

We store information that we collect through cookies and log files to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our website, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. This information may also be used to help improve our services overall. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

_Cookies:_  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information while a user is visiting our site. We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. For the session cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance their experience on our site. By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still browse our site, however they will not be able to buy or sell tickets. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

StubHub is currently using and has contracted with Omniture, a third party, to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers. We use the information to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. To do this, we use web beacons and cookies provided by Omniture on this site. By supplementing our records, this information helps us learn things like what pages are most attractive to our visitors, which of our products most interest our customers, and what kinds of offers our customers like to see. StubHub owns this data and controls how it may and may not be used. If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy, you can "opt-out" of this website analysis tool by clicking here <http://www.omniture.com/privacy#optout>.

_Log Files:_  
Like most standard website servers, we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring pages, platform type, date/time stamp. IP addresses, etc. are linked to personally identifiable information. We use Log Files in error diagnostics, session management and determining our advertising efficacy.

**Communications from the Site**

_Transactions and Service Announcements:_   
Members who buy or sell tickets will receive a number of emails throughout the transaction process and they may sometimes receive phone calls from our Customer Service department to ensure smooth transactions. We may also occasionally send out service-related announcements, for instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance. Generally, these communications are not promotional in nature, and users will receive them as long as their accounts are open.

_Special Offers, Newsletters and Updates:_   
Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications, as explained in the _Choice and opt-out_ section below.

_Customer Service:_   
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services. We respond to issues relating to a user's account via email or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

_Choice and opt-out:_  
A user can change their opt-in or opt-out status in several ways:

From a Newsletter: Click on the "Unsubscribe" link within the email or go to _<http://www.stubhub.com/unsubscribe/>_. If the site does not recognize you, please enter your email address and click submit. The next step is to select the alerts which you no longer wish to receive and click the “unsubscribe” button. If the site does recognize you, you do not have to enter your email address. Simply select the alerts which you no longer wish to receive and click the “unsubscribe” button. 

From the website: If you have a username and password, login to your account by clicking the Login link on the home page. Then click the My Account link on the top navigation bar. Once in My Account, you can then update your alerts within “My Preferences.” Please go to the Contact Preferences section and you can revise alerts by adding or removing checks from the radio buttons in My StubHub alerts section. Then click the “Save” button. 

If you do not have a registered account, go to 

_<http://www.stubhub.com/unsubscribe/>_

. If the site does not recognize you, please enter your email address and click submit. Select the alerts you no longer wish to receive and click the “unsubscribe” button. If the site does recognize you, you do not have to enter your email address. Simply select the alerts which you no longer wish to receive and click the “unsubscribe” button. 

_Referral Tools_ _:  
_If you choose to use our referral services, we ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a copy of the email. StubHub or our service providers store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.  Your friend may contact us at [customerservice@stubhub.com](mailto:customerservice@stubhub.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Testimonials and Photo Usage**

If you submit testimonials, photos, blogs, writings, customer satisfaction surveys or other writings or media in connection with use of StubHub and its services, user approves the right to use the user's name, home city and such writings, or media testimonials in connection with StubHub's marketing and publicity efforts in any and all media in perpetuity. Said media shall include, without limitation, print, radio, television, internet, email, magazine and any other form of communication whether now known or hereafter devised.

No consideration is being paid for this release, and the user understands that StubHub is relying on this release without consideration if it avails itself of any or all of the rights granted herein. 

**Sharing Information**

At StubHub, we care about your privacy. We will not share your credit card number or any other financial information with any third party except for the verification purposes mentioned above. We may share your personal information with third parties in the following instances:

_Within Our Corporate Family:  
_We may share information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures or other companies under common control, where it may be used to provide joint services or for purposes such as internal statistics, strategic decision-making, customer verification, fraud prevention and security. 

_Legal Disclaimer:_  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may disclose personal information when required by law or under the good-faith belief that such action is necessary under applicable law. We may disclose personal information in order to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We also share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, to protect our property or interests or that of our agents and employees, and to protect personal safety or the public.

_Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable):_  
We share some aggregated demographic information (age, zip codes) with some of our partners. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. 

_Co-Branded Partners:_  
The contact information and transaction data (excluding credit card numbers) provided by customers on our co-branded sites and registered or transacted through a partner's co-branded StubHub are essentially shared with the owner of that co-branded website. Your choices about being contacted are included with that information so that partner can respect your preferences. Refer to that website's privacy policy for information on how they will handle your information. 

_Third Party Service Providers:_  
We may disclose information about individual users to third parties who provide services to StubHub. These third parties provide a variety of services to StubHub, including, without limitation, verifying credit card information, fulfilling ticket orders via courier delivery, processing credit card transactions, and disbursing payments to sellers. In addition, these services may include enhancing the information StubHub collects about its customers. We may also use third-party email providers to assist with sending our marketing emails. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. Any personally identifiable information that StubHub shares with its service providers may only be used to provide services to StubHub and the service providers will not be given permission to use such information for other purposes.

_Business Transitions:_  
In the event StubHub goes through a business transition, such as a merger, an acquisition by another company, or a sale of all or a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via prominent notice on our website for 30 days after a change of ownership or control of their personal information, if personal information will be used contrary to this policy. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, users will be given the option to continue sharing their information consistent with our notification of changes section. However, nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with the ability of StubHub to transfer all or part of its business and/or assets (including the Site), for any purposes, without any limitation whatsoever. StubHub specifically reserves the right to transfer or share a copy of personally identifiable information collected from its Site to the buyer of that portion of its business relating to that information. 

**Security**

This website takes every reasonable precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with encryption software, currently SSL encryption. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just 'surfing'. While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also protect user-information off-line. Access to all users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted to our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. The servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, behind a locked cage at a professional hosting company. Although we endeavor to create secure and reliable Sites and to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. You hereby acknowledge that StubHub is not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the Internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.

**External Links**

The Site contains links to other websites maintained by third parties. Please be aware that StubHub exercises no control over linked sites and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such sites. Each linked site maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures, and you are encouraged to view the privacy policies of these other sites before providing any personal information.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

Effective [3/14/07]
